http://www.cardiff-astronomical-society.co.uk/privacy-policy

katherine.compton@virgin.net
Navigate to...
-  Buy and Sell
-  CAS Handbooks (1979-2020)
-  CAS Newsletters (2011-19)
-  Easyfundraising - Help the Society to raise funs
-  Ultimate Telescope Buying Guide - courtesy of Michelle Phillips, content writer for Geekwrapped
-  Dictionary of Astronomical Terms
-  Astonishing - Planet Earth is really TINY!
Buy and Sell
CAS Handbooks (1979-2020)
CAS Newsletters (2011-19)
Easyfundraising - Help the Society to raise funs
Ultimate Telescope Buying Guide - courtesy of Michelle Phillips, content writer for Geekwrapped
Dictionary of Astronomical Terms
Astonishing - Planet Earth is really TINY!
CAS Privacy Policy
The Cardiff Astronomical Society (CAS) was established in 1975 and is one of the largest amateur astronomical societies in the UK. CAS became a registered charity in October 2016 (charity number 1169953).We are committed to respecting your privacy and keeping your personal information safe. Since the protection of your privacy is of great importance to us, we have created this privacy policy to communicate our practices regarding the collection and dissemination of personal information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as a name, postal address, telephone number, email address (if supplied), date of birth (in respect of Junior members of the Society), membership start and renewal dates, skills possessed (if provided), method of payment of membership subscription, or information as to whether you are a taxpayer to help us to claim Gift Aid, or any other information provided to us by our members or other individuals.This policy does not extend to external sites linked from our website - please check with these organisations for their policies regarding data privacy, including the use of "cookies". We will not rent, swap or sell your personal information to any other organisations.The legal basis that we rely on for processing your data will depend upon the circumstances in which it is being collected and used, but will in most cases fall into one of the following categories:
> where you have provided your consent to allow us to use your data in a certain way
> where the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you
> where the processing is necessary for the Society to meet a legal obligation.If you are a member of the Society, we need to hold your personal information so that we can keep our register of members up-to-date and to provide you with details about our events and activities, usually by the means of our quarterly Newsletters, and to manage membership applications and reminders/renewals. Where you give us consent, we may also use your personal data to send you marketing and fundraising communications relating to the Society's services and related activities. Where consent has been given we will also use your personal information to process Gift Aid donations. We do not collect sensitive personal information about our members or other individuals in any circumstances. We do not store credit/debit card details or share membership payment details with any third parties. All personal information held by the Society is accessible only by specifically designated officers of the Society who require access to perform their duties. Principally, the designated officers are the Society's Membership Secretary and Treasurer. When members of the Society make payments online, we use a secure server and encryption to protect your financial and other personal information during transmission.We will usually collect personal information about you when you:
> ask about our activities
> apply to become a member of CAS or renew your membership
> make a donation or sign up to an event
> telephone, write, email, contact us online or otherwise provide us with your personal information.We may disclose your personal information when required to by law, for example, to HMRC for tax purposes or to police forces for the prevention or detection of crime. We will share your data in other circumstances only if we have your explicit and informed consent.When someone visits the CAS website http://www.cardiff-astronomical-society.co.uk/ we use a third-party service, currently Webfactory, to collect standard internet log in information and details of behaviour patterns. This information is processed in a way which does not identify anyone. Where we have given you a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping the password confidential. You agree not to share that password with anyone else.The Society is committed to protecting the safety and privacy of children and vulnerable adults. See a copy of our "Policy on Child Protection and the Protection of Vulnerable Adults" - https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cdn.webfactore.co.uk/sr_607003.pdfWe are committed to protecting the privacy of young people who are Junior members of the Society or who take part in educational events at schools and elsewhere including at the Society's Observatory. Where appropriate we will seek consent from a parent, guardian or carer before collecting information about young people aged under 16.We operate a number of social media pages (including Facebook and Twitter). Although this policy covers how we will use any data collected from those pages it does not cover how the providers of social media websites will use your information. Please ensure you read the privacy policy of the social media website before sharing data and make use of the privacy settings and reporting mechanisms to control how your data is use.You can change your mind at any time about how we contact you and you can ask us to stop contacting you. You can help us keep our records accurate and up-to-date by telling us when your contact details and other personal information changes. Please contact the Society's Membership Secretary by email at Membership.Secretary@cardiff-astronomical-society.co.uk or by post to the CAS Membership Secretary, Katherine Compton, 62 Donald Street, Cardiff, CF24 4TR and she will make the changes for you.We are moving to an "opt-in only" communications policy. This means that we will send communications only to members who have explicitly stated that they are happy for us to do so via their preferred channel(s): email or post.We will retain your personal information only for as long as you have an active relationship with CAS. If you cease to have an active relationship with us or request to receive no further contact, we may retain some basic information to avoid sending you unwanted materials in the future, and to ensure that we do not accidentally duplicate information.You may, in relation to personal data that you have given to the Society, make a "data subject request" to receive a copy of the personal data the Society holds on you. This information will be provided to you, normally within one month, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable form. You may also request that such information is transmitted by the Society directly to another organisation if this is technically feasible. Please contact the Society's Membership Secretary by email or by post as above. We will not charge to provide this information to you. We may require proof of identity of the person making the request. You have the right to ask us to correct any information that you think is inaccurate by contacting the Society's Membership Secretary as above. You also have the right at any time to seek the removal of any personal data that the Society holds on you and to restrict the processing that the Society can undertake using such data. In addition, you have the right to withdraw at any time any consent you have given to the Society in relation to the collection and processing of your personal data.We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on the Society's website and/or by contacting you directly.If you have any questions, comments or suggestions, please let us know by contacting the Society's Membership Secretary by email or post as above.You have the right to lodge a complaint or express a concern about the Society's use of your personal data at any time with the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) online via https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/ or using one of the following methods: By post: 	Information Commissioner's Office2nd floorChurchill HouseChurchill wayCardiffCF10 2HHBy telephone: 	Tel: 029 2067 8400By email:	 wales@ico.org.uk This Privacy Policy was last updated on 15 May 2018.
Contact Us
Privacy Policy
Disclaimer
To report spelling corrections, incorrect facts or broken links please contact: webmaster@cardiff-astronomical-society.co.uk Cardiff Astronomical Society became a Charitable Incorporated Organisation on 31st October 2016. Registered Charity Number: 1169953
Website Design by Webfactory
×
×
×
